<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ucscieee.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ucscieee.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-28T12:16:55+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">IEEE Student Branch of UCSC</title><subtitle>IEEE student branch of University of Colombo School of Computing was established in 2011 and has achieved great success during past few years. Student branch has been formed with the participation and contribution of all four batches of University of Colombo School of Computing and it has been organizing many activities to enhance professional development of the students.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">GameRush 2019</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2019/11/30/gamerush.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GameRush 2019" /><published>2019-11-30T02:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-30T02:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2019/11/30/gamerush</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2019/11/30/gamerush.html">&lt;p&gt;Game Rush was a 24 hour game development hackathon organized by the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC. This is a hackathon, aimed at building some unique and interesting games. By the competition day, each team, have to build a fully functional web or mobile game. This is the first time we organized this unique Gameathon.This hackathon was open to university undergraduates all around the country who are, or aspire to game developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision behind organizing this first time event, was based on the intention to provide a Hackathon experience, centered around exploration and experimentation for the participants who brainstormed to develop an idea into a game while also providing a platform to show their skills to industry representatives and receive mentoring from them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the initial preparation, we planned to hold a series of workshops about Game Development prior to the hackathon with the contribution of experts in the Industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key objective was to enhance the game development skills of the students and providing
them with the opportunity to present their innovative ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build edutainment based games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provides an opportunity to present their games to seek partnerships/investments in publishing the game.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourages students from different backgrounds like gamers, programmers, designers to participate in a single course as the process of developing a game involves design and artistic expression.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a networking platform for students with interests in Game Development and related areas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide the students with an opportunity to acquire comprehensive knowledge on bleeding edge technologies and industry trends in Game development arena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;event-details&quot;&gt;Event details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;workshop-1&quot;&gt;Workshop 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First workshop of Game Rush was held on the 6th of july at Microsoft Sri Lanka.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were around 50 participants and two most experienced and famous IT professionals from the industry who conducted the workshop. 
First speaker was Chanux Bro who is Srilanka’s top tech reviewer,and a software engineer &amp;amp; social media consultant by profession at Sinlix. He gave an excellent start by an interactive session on introduction to game development. He further discussed about the history of game development and latest trends in game development.
The second speaker was Mr.Uditha Sampath Bandara(MVP) who is the CEO &amp;amp; founder of Blue chip training and consulting.Also he is the south Asia’s first Directx MVP(most valuable professional). He conducted the 2nd half of the workshop by giving a description about game development techniques.He also illustrated the uses of game development and discussed effective ways of developing games using Unity game engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/gamerush/workshop_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;workshop-2&quot;&gt;Workshop 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second workshop of the workshop series of Game rush took place on the 31st of August at UCSC Premises.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were more than 100 participants and the workshop was successfully conducted by Team Prodigi interactive, a well reputed organization in game development industry  founded by Mr. Yasith Nayana.The workshop 2 was based on basics of Unity engine and also they routed the participants about Game Development Pipelines taking their own homegrown game “Threta” as a case study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/gamerush/workshop_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;workshop-3&quot;&gt;Workshop 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third workshop of Game Rush was successfully held on the 2nd of November 2019 at UCSC premises.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guest speaker was Mr. Bhasura Gunawardhana; an experienced professional in the industry. there was also an informative session conducted by an eminent team of Software Engineers from SimCentric Technologies on Introduction to UE4 Gameplay Framework. The Workshop was further ignited by the presence of a Team from Ram Studio who developed Extraction Valley Devil’s Curse- First ever grand scale multiplayer game in Sri Lanka  to share their knowledge on Game Development using Unreal Game Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/gamerush/workshop_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Workshop 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-hackathon&quot;&gt;Final Hackathon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the workshop series, the registrations for the final hackathon were opened.Over 25 mind-blowing proposals we selected the top 10 proposals for the final hackathon and it was held on 30th of November 2019 from 8.00am onwards at UCSC premises. Throughout the day the contestants were free to ask anything about game Development and any clarifications about their project from the mentors. A team from Arimac &amp;amp; SimCentric joined as mentors for the hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/content/gamerush/hackathon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final Hackathon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-matrix-sprinter&quot;&gt;The Matrix Sprinter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;by-team-404-of-university-of-moratuwa&quot;&gt;By Team 404 of University of Moratuwa&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an Action RPG Game. The player will see everything as a simulation generated by the items he wears. The player must complete every level of the game until he escapes the facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;augmented-reality-table-tennis&quot;&gt;Augmented Reality Table Tennis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;by-team-btb-of-university-of-moratuwa&quot;&gt;By Team BTB of University of Moratuwa&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An augmented reality Table Tennis game that can be played using two smartphones connected wirelessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;hard-duos&quot;&gt;Hard Duos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;by-team-ghost-of-university-of-colombo-school-of-computing&quot;&gt;By Team Ghost of University of Colombo School of Computing&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard Duos is a third person, hero based, 1 vs 1 multiplayer, attacker-defender
game. Two champions will battle in an arena where both gets to attack and defend. Player
with two point advantage wins.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">Game Rush was a 24 hour game development hackathon organized by the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC. This is a hackathon, aimed at building some unique and interesting games. By the competition day, each team, have to build a fully functional web or mobile game. This is the first time we organized this unique Gameathon.This hackathon was open to university undergraduates all around the country who are, or aspire to game developers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/gamerush/cover.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Induction 2019</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2019/04/10/induction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Induction 2019" /><published>2019-04-10T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2019/04/10/induction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2019/04/10/induction.html">&lt;p&gt;IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main goal of hosting IEEEXtreme was to uplift the programming skills of UCSC undergraduates as well as achieve global recognition through obtaining ranks. The organizing committee who were in charge of handling the logistics put a great effort into the success of the event. And few algorithmic workshops were done in prior months to get the new participants familiar with the coding environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/induction.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEEXtreme 11.0</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/11/29/ieeextreme-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEEXtreme 11.0" /><published>2017-11-29T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-29T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/11/29/ieeextreme-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/11/29/ieeextreme-11.html">&lt;p&gt;IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem-solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members from IEEE Student Branch of UCSC competed online as teams, testing their skills against each other. Being one of the most active student branches in IEEE Region 10, IEEE Student Branch of UCSC hosted the event for more than 100 undergraduates at the university premises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of hosting IEEEXtreme was to uplift the programming skills of UCSC undergraduates as well as achieve global recognition through obtaining ranks. The organizing committee who were in charge of handling the logistics put a great effort into the success of the event. And few algorithmic workshops were done in prior months to get the new participants familiar with the coding environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem-solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/ieeextreme11.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">UCSC IEEE Day 2017</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/10/19/ieee-day-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCSC IEEE Day 2017" /><published>2017-10-19T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/10/19/ieee-day-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/10/19/ieee-day-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;UCSC IEEE Day 2017 was celebrated with much grace and grandeur on 11th of October 2017 at the New Arts Theatre of University of Colombo. Each year UCSC has never failed to mark this event, above expectation and this year is no exception in that regard. This year the theme of the event was “For an age when machines start thinking”, a theme very relevant to the current scenarios happening all over the world. This event was not restricted just to this single day. There were some pre-events including a lot of tricky brain teasers. And of course on this special day, students from universities all around the island have attended and made their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCSC IEEE Day 2017 was planned under three major technical zones, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Fast Data. Our guest speaker, Mr. Samudra Kanakearachchi, Solution Architect at 99X Technologies delivered a speech on Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence. Mr. Dilantha Malagamuwa, car race driver and champion of many racing contests, mesmerized the audience with his own story about his personal journey towards victory and the hardships and challenges he had to face on his way. And then, Mr. Faris Ismail, CEO/MD - Achievers through his speech, inspired the entire audience to work towards a developed Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the celebration mode was on, Director of University of Colombo School of Computing, Professor K.P. Hewagamage cut the cake and then he delivered a short speech about the event. Following a short break Mr. Aruna Dissanayake, Experienced database architect with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology methodologies, delivered another speech on Fast Data and Data Science. After that, the auditorium was filled with merriment as the fun element came up. That which included innovative competitions went on with super excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the winners of the quiz, the brain teasers, and the selfie contest were given nice gifts. Finally, the event came to a pleasant end. UCSC IEEE Day 2017 certainly reached its benchmark and satisfied all the participants who had come with high hopes as usual. All the best to the organizing committee and the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">UCSC IEEE Day 2017 was celebrated with much grace and grandeur on 11th of October 2017 at the New Arts Theatre of University of Colombo. Each year UCSC has never failed to mark this event, above expectation and this year is no exception in that regard. This year the theme of the event was “For an age when machines start thinking”, a theme very relevant to the current scenarios happening all over the world. This event was not restricted just to this single day. There were some pre-events including a lot of tricky brain teasers. And of course on this special day, students from universities all around the island have attended and made their day.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/IEEEDay.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CloudHack 2017</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/08/24/cloudhack.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CloudHack 2017" /><published>2017-08-24T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-24T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/08/24/cloudhack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/08/24/cloudhack.html">&lt;p&gt;It was a remarkable chapter in the history of IEEE Student Branch of UCSC. The first ever cloud-based hackathon, CloudHack’17 came to an end on 13th of August at UCSC with great success. Now let’s retrace the steps of their successful journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CloudHack’17 was organized by the IEEE Student Branch of University of Colombo School of Computing in collaboration with the Google Developer Group Sri Lanka. The primary intention of the event was to instill the potential of cloud computing as a powerful tool in developing solutions having both real-world implications and demanding computational requirements. It was a 24-hour hackathon and 10 teams consisting of 4 members were selected out of all the applicants from local universities. The event was sponsored by MilenniumIT and Pulse Solutions and the media sponsor was Pahasara UCSC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organizing committee did a tremendous work of planning this event right from the beginning. Two workshops were organized before the event to give an understanding to the participants about cloud technologies. The first introductory workshop was on Google Cloud Platform and Cloud SQL and the second workshop was based on Amazon Web Services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After so much of hard work, the first ever cloud-based hackathon’s opening ceremony took place on 12th of August at UCSC. Prof. K. P. Hewagamage made an inspiring speech as the chief guest and the selected 10 teams started the hackathon at 9 am with so much excitement and energy. The event was well organized to give the best environment for the participants to reach their potentials. There were mentors from Sysco Lab and GDG to help and guide the participants. The teams had to present their ideas to the judges after 20 hours of developing their project ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the award ceremony took place where the winners were awarded cash prizes and the judges with tokens of appreciation. It was an amazing event and a great experience for all the participants. Congratulations for all the winning teams and well wishes to the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC for a successful journey ahead.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sponsors     : MIT, Pulse Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Date        : 2017.08.24&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Venue        : Room W002 at UCSC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audience    : Undergraduates from local universities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">It was a remarkable chapter in the history of IEEE Student Branch of UCSC. The first ever cloud-based hackathon, CloudHack’17 came to an end on 13th of August at UCSC with great success. Now let’s retrace the steps of their successful journey.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/cloudhack.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">UCSC IEEE DAY 2016</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/02/04/ieee-day-2016.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCSC IEEE DAY 2016" /><published>2017-02-04T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-04T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/02/04/ieee-day-2016</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/02/04/ieee-day-2016.html">&lt;p&gt;Celebrating the first time in history, when engineers worldwide and IEEE members gathered to share their technical ideas in 1884, marked the commencement of a new journey of IEEE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IEEE Day theme is “Leveraging Technology for a Better Tomorrow”. While the world benefits from what’s new, IEEE focuses on what’s next. Worldwide celebrations demonstrate the way thousands of IEEE members in the local community join together to collaborate on ideas that leverage technology for a better tomorrow. While there were a lot of celebrations  happening around the globe celebrating the IEEE Day 2016 the 7th edition, UCSC IEEE student branch also celebrated the IEEE Day inspired with the theme of  “Innovation and Emerging Tech” on 4th of October at the University of Colombo School of Computing premises. The main objective of this event was to inspire and encourage the youth to obtain IEEE membership in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was organized at a greater scale. It was a success from the beginning. As we expected there was about 200 audience including undergraduates from UCSC and other universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the presentation of the introductory videos and speeches, the inauguration of IEEE was celebrated by cutting the traditional cake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much vital and attractive lecture sessions were conducted based on Machine Learning by Keshan Sodimana, Recent Trends in Cyber Security by Ayoma Wijethunga and Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality by  Senior Director and Architecture, Mr. Anjana Somathilake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most entertaining part of the event is the interactive session conducted for participants. They were seemed more enthusiastic in this session. The session was included games and Quiz competition which was made by UCSC IEEE members using an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hat passing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treasure hunt based on app most likely to the Pokémon game.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ice-breaking – break the cup hill game including online games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fancy gifts were awarded to the winners of the above-mentioned games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most enthusiastic part of the session was quiz competition. It was all about how fast you can think of the answer and the IQ knowledge you got. Two participants were able to win the competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world demands the quality of youth; not a time of life, but a state of mind to achieve the greatest, a quality of imagination, a predominance of courage over the timidity, appetite for adventure over the love of ease. As the IEEE student branch of the nation’s premier IT institute, it is their duty to admonish the young generation about the latest technology. Hence the event was able to mark a great success and end successfully with the support of the dedicated members of IEEE Student Branch of UCSC and the gold sponsor,  Cake Labs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">Celebrating the first time in history, when engineers worldwide and IEEE members gathered to share their technical ideas in 1884, marked the commencement of a new journey of IEEE.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/ieeedays.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEEXtreme 10.0</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/ieeextreme-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEEXtreme 10.0" /><published>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/ieeextreme-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/ieeextreme-10.html">&lt;p&gt;IEEEXtreme 10.0, the most competitive and challenging 24-hour global programming competition was commenced at 05.30 a.m in Sri Lankan time on 22nd of October 2016. The event at UCSC was organized by the UCSC IEEE Student Branch. More than 100 teams fervently participated for the Xtreme competition from the UCSC, including the UCSC IEEE Student Branch members. Teams were formed of three members each, proctored by a senior IEEE member. All the teams were ambitious and eager to prove themselves. The solutions could be coded using C, C++, C#, Java, Python, Ruby, Perl, or PHP, the supportive languages for this competition. As the first problem showed up on the screens the competition launched globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problems were hard indeed. But the competitors were enjoying the experience to the best with their team members. Teamwork and immense efforts always do pay off and as a result, most of the teams were climbing higher and higher in the competition. In the interim, refreshments were provided to the competitors for their comfort throughout the competition by the logistics team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the point that UCSC undergraduates were competing since 2011 in the IEEEXtreme Programming Competition, it was a definite fact that this competition is going to prove and elaborate the skills of the UCSC undergraduates globally in as much as it did in the previous years. The Pre IEEEXtreme sessions helped the students to gear up and equip themselves with well-furnished problem-solving skills and it helped the students to be familiar with the problem types and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;108 teams to be exact participated from the UCSC for IEEEXtreme 10.0.  41% (44 teams) of those teams were holding country ranks below 100. The participation of the UCSC undergraduates in this competition was spaced out even among the other universities of the region as the event was promoted frequently within the university and the UCSC IEEE Student Branch is working on stimulating and strengthening the skills of the undergraduates through awareness programs and more Pre Extreme sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are providing our utmost gratitude to all the lecturers and the staff for supporting and being there for us in every way they can. Everybody at UCSC helped in a way to make this event a success. Even the non-participants stayed up all night providing refreshments to the competitors. And also we are proud of all the hard work and achievements of the competitors and congratulate them all to achieve more and more to make UCSC proud.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">IEEEXtreme 10.0, the most competitive and challenging 24-hour global programming competition was commenced at 05.30 a.m in Sri Lankan time on 22nd of October 2016. The event at UCSC was organized by the UCSC IEEE Student Branch. More than 100 teams fervently participated for the Xtreme competition from the UCSC, including the UCSC IEEE Student Branch members. Teams were formed of three members each, proctored by a senior IEEE member. All the teams were ambitious and eager to prove themselves. The solutions could be coded using C, C++, C#, Java, Python, Ruby, Perl, or PHP, the supportive languages for this competition. As the first problem showed up on the screens the competition launched globally.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Achievements of IEEEXtreme 10.0</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/ieeextreme-10-achivement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Achievements of IEEEXtreme 10.0" /><published>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/ieeextreme-10-achivement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/ieeextreme-10-achivement.html">&lt;p&gt;As we all know IEEEXtreme is a worldwide programming competition that tests our analytical skills and thinking ability to solve a particular problem. When we look at UCSC, there were hundreds of students who participated in the competition. Teams were formed of three members each, guided by a senior IEEE member. There were hard questions indeed but some were easy which should be all coded using C, C++, C#, Java, Python, Ruby, Perl, or PHP, the supportive languages for this competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about what we achieved in competing in IEEEXtreme 10.0 is, that as we are a team running forward to answer all questions in a given period of time, the team members must have sound knowledge, communication skills, and cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UCSC undergraduates were competing since 2011 in the IEEEXtreme competitions and it was certain that this competition is going to prove and intricate the skills of UCSC undergraduates globally as much as they did in previous years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all 109 teams participated most of the teams had done well. Team Morpheus is ranked top in UCSC with Sulochana Kodithuwakku, Hasanga Somarathna and Madusha Ushan in the team. They were ranked seventh in the country with a region rank of 66 and world rank of 195. Teams which achieved second and third places in UCSC team threadsafe and team Raconteurs ranked seventh and twenty-first places in the country respectively whilst the world ranks were 198 and 259 respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;109 teams out of the 297 teams from Sri Lanka were from UCSC. Approximately 37% of the Sri Lankan contribution was made from UCSC alone. 44 teams managed to get hold of ranks inside the first hundred within Sri Lanka. Remarkably, 25 teams have achieved positions within the first 200 teams of the R10 region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a huge success compared with the last year’s achievements. All the teams were very happy about their performance at IEEEXtreme 10.0 and they all hope to take part in IEEEXtreme 11.0 in the upcoming year. As undergraduates of UCSC, we are giving our greatest gratitude to IEEE Student Branch of UCSC as well as the mentors who helped us throughout the competition. We also congratulate the teams who managed to secure good ranks in the competition.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">As we all know IEEEXtreme is a worldwide programming competition that tests our analytical skills and thinking ability to solve a particular problem. When we look at UCSC, there were hundreds of students who participated in the competition. Teams were formed of three members each, guided by a senior IEEE member. There were hard questions indeed but some were easy which should be all coded using C, C++, C#, Java, Python, Ruby, Perl, or PHP, the supportive languages for this competition.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/achieve.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pre IEEEXtreme Programming Competition 1.0</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/prextreme-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pre IEEEXtreme Programming Competition 1.0" /><published>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/prextreme-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/prextreme-1.html">&lt;p&gt;It was the 24th of September 2016. Almost all the students of UCSC gathered in the morning to UCSC premises with enthusiastic minds to participate in the Pre IEEEXtreme Programming Competition 1.0. This was a 10-hour in-site coding competition organized by the IEEE student branch for internal students of UCSC with the main objective of preparing the undergraduates for IEEEXtreme 10.0. Participants competed as groups of 3 members each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition started at 8.00a.m. on the 4th floor of UCSC. Initially,  there were 4 questions from the easy category. There were 3 types of questions, easy, medium and hard. Each of those easy type questions carried 100-150 points. Each hour they released a challenge and these challenges were getting harder gradually. The final challenge was the hardest one which carried 300 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the students attempted the challenges throughout the competition with the same enthusiasm which they had in the morning. Members of each team got together and solved the problems while discussing and helping each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students were given their lunch. After having their lunch,  they started to attempt the challenges again. Most of the students used python as the language while some others attempt them using different languages such as C++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 6.00 p.m. competition was finished and winners were announced. Team ‘void_xtream’ was the team who won the first place and the members of the team were Oshan Mudannayake, Sumedha Dissanayake and Pramodya Abeysinghe. The second place was won by team ‘whileloop_1’ and the third place was won by ‘dire’ team ‘’. Winners received book vouchers as gifts. The competition was wind up by taking the group photo of the participants. This competition had given all the participants the clear idea about IEEEXtreme and this made them familiar to the IEEEXtreme. We hope as the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC succeeded in accomplishing our main objective of Pre Xtreme Programming Competition 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">It was the 24th of September 2016. Almost all the students of UCSC gathered in the morning to UCSC premises with enthusiastic minds to participate in the Pre IEEEXtreme Programming Competition 1.0. This was a 10-hour in-site coding competition organized by the IEEE student branch for internal students of UCSC with the main objective of preparing the undergraduates for IEEEXtreme 10.0. Participants competed as groups of 3 members each.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/pre1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SLT e-Sports Reid Cyber Wars 2.0</title><link href="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/reid-wars.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SLT e-Sports Reid Cyber Wars 2.0" /><published>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/reid-wars</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ucscieee.com/2017/01/31/reid-wars.html">&lt;p&gt;Inter-University Gaming Championship 2016 - “Let the Battle Begins”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SLT e-Sports Reid Cyber Wars 2.0 (RCW 2.0) was held on 12th May 2016 from 8 a.m. onwards at the University of Colombo School of Computing (UCSC) premises. This was the second chapter of the RCW and the first time to be opened up as Inter-University Gaming Championship. SLT e-Sports Reid Cyber Wars 2.0 was organized by the Computer Science Society of University of Colombo (CompSoc) and the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC together with the sole sponsor Sri Lanka Telecom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call of Duty 4 – Modern Warfare (5 vs 5) was the main highlight in Reid Cyber Wars 2.0. 27 teams were registered for the gaming event. All teams battled with the intention, “No Mercy for Enemy”. In the end ‘Moratu Yakku’ from the University of Moratuwa and ‘Mindless Outlaws’ from the University of Rajarata came to the final. After a breath-taking battle ‘Moratu Yakku’ from University of Moratuwa became the champions of Call of Duty 4- Modern Warfare in Reid Cyber Wars 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need for Speed (NFS) Most Wanted “I feel the Need … The Need for Speed” was also one of the most looked forward events in the Reid Cyber Wars 2.0. It was raced in 2 categories as boys and girls as a knockout tournament. After an exciting and thrilling series of races, the winner of the boys’ category was Buddhika Sameera and the winner of the girls’ category was Chanduni Wickramasinghe at RCW 2.0.\r\n\r\n“I’ll make weapons from your bones” such is the excitement of Mortal Kombat X. Mortal Kombat X was there for boys and girls in 2 separate categories this year. The boys’ category winner was Dulaj Gunawardena from the University of Moratuwa and the girls’ category winner was Dilini Weerasinghe from the University of Colombo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll make weapons from your bones” such is the excitement of Mortal Kombat X. Mortal Kombat X was there for boys and girls in 2 separate categories this year. The boys’ category winner was Dulaj Gunawardena from the University of Moratuwa and the girls’ category winner was Dilini Weerasinghe from the University of Colombo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were also some mini-games to be contested in the Reid Cyber Wars 2.0.  The winner of Piano Tiles game was Nalinda Wanigasekera and Mishari Tamara was the winner of drowning bunny game. There were also games such as Crossy Road, Fruit Ninja, and Game of Thoughts. The winner of Crossy Road was Vidura Dantanarayana. Wishva Hettige was the winner of the Fruit Ninja Game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game of Thoughts is a game created by four students of University of Colombo School of Computing and it was first introduced in the Reid Cyber Wars 2.0. Game of Thoughts is a survival game and to survive in this game the players need to collect cells. Game of thoughts is a multiplayer game. Therefore, as-as to survive in Game of Thoughts the players need to attack other players and get their cells. Buddhika Dahanayake was the winner of Game of Thoughts in Reid Cyber Wars 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reid Cyber Wars 2.0 organized by the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC and Computer Science Society of UOC was in overall a total success at the end. The event was filled with action and the most sought out titles of the gaming world were awarded to the righteous.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">Inter-University Gaming Championship 2016 - “Let the Battle Begins”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ucscieee.com/sports.jpg" /></entry></feed>