<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/official-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/official-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-17T17:41:06+00:00</updated><id>/official-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">IEEE Student Branch of UCSC</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Induction</title><link href="/official-website/2019/04/10/induction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Induction" /><published>2019-04-10T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/official-website/2019/04/10/induction</id><content type="html" xml:base="/official-website/2019/04/10/induction.html">&lt;p&gt;IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main goal of hosting IEEEXtreme was to uplift the programming skills of UCSC undergraduates as well as achieve global recognition through obtaining ranks. The organizing committee who were in charge of handling the logistics put a great effort into the success of the event. And few algorithmic workshops were done in prior months to get the new participants familiar with the coding environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/official-website/induction.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEEXtreme 11.0</title><link href="/official-website/2019/03/01/ieeextreme-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEEXtreme 11.0" /><published>2019-03-01T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-01T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/official-website/2019/03/01/ieeextreme-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="/official-website/2019/03/01/ieeextreme-11.html">&lt;p&gt;IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members from IEEE Student Branch of UCSC competed online as teams, testing their skills against each other. Being one of the most active student branches in IEEE Region 10, IEEE Student Branch of UCSC hosted the event for more than 100 undergraduates at the university premises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main goal of hosting IEEEXtreme was to uplift the programming skills of UCSC undergraduates as well as achieve global recognition through obtaining ranks. The organizing committee who were in charge of handling the logistics put a great effort into the success of the event. And few algorithmic workshops were done in prior months to get the new participants familiar with the coding environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">IEEEXtreme 11.0 is a prestigious coding challenge hosted by IEEE to bring in talented coders from all around the world into an arena of problem solving and algorithmic wizardry for a period of 24 hours.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UCSC IEEE Day 2017</title><link href="/official-website/2019/02/15/ieee-day-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UCSC IEEE Day 2017" /><published>2019-02-15T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/official-website/2019/02/15/ieee-day-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="/official-website/2019/02/15/ieee-day-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;UCSC IEEE Day 2017 was celebrated with much grace and grandeur on 11th of October 2017 at the New Arts Theatre of University of Colombo. Each year UCSC has never failed to mark this event, above expectation and this year is no exception in that regard. This year the theme of the event was “For an age when machines start thinking”, a theme very relevant to the current scenarios happening all over the world. This event was not restricted just to this single day. There were some pre-events including a lot of tricky brain teasers. And of course on this special day, students from universities all around the island have attended and made their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCSC IEEE Day 2017 was planned under three major technical zones, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning and Fast Data. Our guest speaker, Mr. Samudra Kanakearachchi, Solution Architect at 99X Technologies delivered a speech on Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence. Mr. Dilantha Malagamuwa, car race driver and champion of many racing contests, mesmerized the audience with his own story about his personal journey towards victory and the hardships and challenges he had to face on his way. And then, Mr. Faris Ismail, CEO/MD - Achievers through his speech, inspired the entire audience to work towards a developed Sri Lanka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the celebration mode was on, Director of University of Colombo School of Computing, Professor K.P. Hewagamage cut the cake and then he delivered a short speech about the event. Following a short break Mr. Aruna Dissanayake, Experienced database architect with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology methodologies, delivered another speech on Fast Data and Data Science. After that, the auditorium was filled with merriment as the fun element came up. That which included innovative competitions went on with super excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the winners of the quiz, the brain teasers and the selfie contest were given nice gifts. Finally the event came to a pleasant end. UCSC IEEE Day 2017 certainly reached its bench mark and satisfied all the participants who had come with high hopes as usual. All the best to the organizing committee and the IEEE Student Branch of UCSC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>UdeshUK</name></author><summary type="html">UCSC IEEE Day 2017 was celebrated with much grace and grandeur on 11th of October 2017 at the New Arts Theatre of University of Colombo. Each year UCSC has never failed to mark this event, above expectation and this year is no exception in that regard. This year the theme of the event was “For an age when machines start thinking”, a theme very relevant to the current scenarios happening all over the world. This event was not restricted just to this single day. There were some pre-events including a lot of tricky brain teasers. And of course on this special day, students from universities all around the island have attended and made their day.</summary></entry></feed>